Danny Page

daniel.w.page@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/danielwpage | https://dannypage.github.io/

Summary

I am a Software Developer and Data Analyst with 8 years experience, specializing in creating web applications that support decision makers with actionable data. My skills are in developing database-to-web pipelines for Desktop and Mobile platforms.

Skills

Programming Languages: Ruby on Rails, Python/Django, Javascript, SQL

Full-Stack Technologies: Git/Github, Chef, Apache/Nginx, Jenkins Business Intelligence: MicroStrategy, Tableau, Google Analytics, Excel

Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL, Oracle DB, SQLite

Recent Work Experience

Capterra (Gartner Digital Markets)

April 2016 - Present

Full Stack Software Engineer

Arlington, VA

- Implementing features on the **Ruby on Rails, Oracle, and JQuery** stack for multiple applications
- Designing reporting suite within internal RoR app, writing SQL queries to support those reports
- Writing Automated tests for quality control with RSpec
- Managing Wordpress Blog with PHP and Rails API endpoints
- A/B Testing with Optimizely to increase user engagment and revenue

SocialCode

April 2014 – February 2016

Back End Software Engineer

Washington, DC

- Wrote **Python and Django** data platform with RedShift to build internal applications
- Implemented connections to Facebook and Twitter Advertising APIs, kept up with breaking changes
- Developed internal APIs, including creating the schema, code testing, and user feedback
- Wrote automated tests for quality control and Celery tasks for automated crawling
- Designed administrator front-end application with the React Framework UI

Translōc

January 2013 - March 2014

Raleigh, NC

Back-end Developer / Data Analyst

- Created vehicle management features in **Python and Django**
- Structured data collection and storage in MySQL and created Transit dashboards
- Developed internal metrics to help customers identify actionable improvements for their agency
- Scaled MySQL and MongoDB databases as the company grew in scale

Data Meaning

October – December 2012

Analytics Contractor

Washington, D.C. / Remote

- Consulted with clients to create **MicroStrategy** dashboards to track profits and shipping rates
- Created metrics to be measured for Monthly, Quarterly, and Yearly reports to monitor progress
- Determined correlations and forecasts using hotel customer ratings to determine future revenue

MDeverywhere, Inc.

Ruby On Rails Contractor

April – October 2012

Durham, NC

- Developed API in **Ruby on Rails** flagship application to interface with medical practices and hospitals
- Created reporting to measure insurance claim successes and determine ways to minimize rejections
- Implemented RSpec automated code testing protocols to minimize production server downtime

Knackeo

June 2011 - April 2012

Co-Founder & CEO Raleigh, NC / Remote

- Established database schema in **PostgreSQL** and developed **Ruby on Rails** application
- Continually worked with teachers and students to iterate on the design of the product
- Integrated Analytics and A/B testing to best determine conversions and adoption
- Managed team members' roles and duties to accomplish goals, oversaw front-end development

MicroStrategy

October 2010 - June 2011

Education Consultant

50% Travel / 50% Remote

- Shaped **MicroStrategy** training for various verticals including: Entertainment, Banking, Retail
- Worked with customers to determine the best metrics for success in their company
- Wrote training manuals and delivered presentations in-person and online

AOL

May 2010 - September 2010

Junior Software Engineer

Sterling, VA

- Developed features for the AOL Desktop Browser in C++ and worked with QA to troubleshoot bugs
- Researched future features for further AOL Browser innovations

MicroStrategy

July 2009 - May 2010

Technical Support Engineer

McLean, VA

- Rewarded **MicroStrategy** Certified Engineer certification to create full-stack reporting solutions
- Assisted customers in identifying solutions to create ideal reports and dashboards
- Documented errors for developers to to accurately fix problems and enhance customer experiences

Education

High Point University

Fall 2005 - Spring 2009

B.S. Computer Science / B.S. Mathematics

High Point, NC